<?xml version='1.0' encoding="utf-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xml:lang="zh-CN"
	 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	 xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
	<title>PLT.10 Portlet Context</title>	
	<para>
		The PortletContext interface defines a portlet’s view of the portlet application within
which the portlet is running. Using the PortletContext object, a portlet can log events,
obtain portlet application resources, application and portlet runtime options and set and
store attributes that other portlets and servlets in the portlet application can access.
	</para>
		<section>
			<title>PLT.10.1 Scope of the Portlet Context</title>
			<para>
				。。。
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Portlet Context functionality（Portlet下下文功能）</title>
			<para>
				。。。
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>PLT.10.3 Relationship with the Servlet Context</title>
			<para>
				...
			</para>
			<section>
				<title>PLT.10.3.1 Correspondence(通信) between ServletContext and PortletContext methods</title>
				<para>
					下列方法ServletContext提供，PortletContext也应该提供相同的功能：
					 getAttribute,getAttributeNames, getInitParameter, getInitParameterNames, getMimeType,
getRealPath, getResource, getResourcePaths, getResourceAsStream, log,removeAttribute and setAttribute.
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>PLT.10.4 Portlet Container Runtime Options</title>
			<para>
				The portlet can define additional runtime behavior in the portlet.xml on either the
portlet application level or the portlet level with the container-runtime-option element.
Runtime options that are defined on the application level should be applied to all portlets
in the portlet application. Runtime options that are defined on the portlet level should be
applied for this portlet only and override any runtime options defined on the application
level with the same name.
			</para>
			<para>
				Container runtime options besides the
javax.portlet.actionScopedRequestAttributes option are optional to support by
the portlet container and the portlet can find out which container runtime options are
supported by the portlet container running the portlet via the method
getContainerRuntimeOptions on the PortletContext.
			</para>
			<para>
The getContainerRuntimeOptions method returns an enumeration of type String
containing the keys of all container runtime options that the current portlet container supports.
			</para>				
			<section>
				<title>PLT.10.4.1 Runtime Option javax.portlet.escapeXml</title>
				<para>
					... 
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>PLT.10.4.2 Runtime Option javax.portlet.renderHeaders</title>
				<para>
					...
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>PLT.10.4.3 Runtime Option javax.portlet.servletDefaultSessionScope</title>
				<para>
					...
				</para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>PLT.10.4.4 Runtime Option javax.portlet.actionScopedRequestAttributes</title>
				<para>
					...
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
</chapter>