<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:lang="zh-CN" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:ns5="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:ns4="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:ns3="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>PLT.1 Preface 前言</title>

  <para>。。。</para>

  <section>
    <title>PLT.1.1 Additional Sources</title>

    <para>The specification is intended to be a complete and clear explanation
    of Java portlets, but if questions remain the following may be
    consulted:</para>

    <para>A reference implementation (RI) has been made available which
    provides a behavioral benchmark for this specification. Where the
    specification leaves implementation of a particular feature open to
    interpretation, implementators may use the reference implementation as a
    model of how to carry out the intention of the specification</para>

    <para>A Technology Compatibility Kit (TCK) has been provided for assessing
    whether implementations meet the compatibility requirements of the JavaTM
    Portlet API standard. The test results have normative value for resolving
    questions about whether an implementation is standard</para>

    <para>If further clarification is required, the working group for the
    JavaTM Portlet API under the Java Community Process should be consulted,
    and is the final arbiter of such issues</para>

    <para>Comments and feedback are welcomed, and will be used to improve
    future versions.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>PLT.1.2 Who Should Read This Specification</title>

    <para>The intended audience for this specification includes the following
    groups:</para>

    <para>a. Portal server vendors that want to provide portlet containers
    that conform to this standard</para>

    <para>b.Authoring tool developers that want to support web applications
    that conform to this specification</para>

    <para>c.Experienced portlet authors who want to understand the underlying
    mechanisms of portlet technology</para>

    <para>We emphasize that this specification is not a user’s guide for
    portlet developers and is not intended to be used as such.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>PLT.1.3 API Reference API参考</title>

    <para>An accompanying javadoc™, includes the full specifications of
    classes, interfaces, and method signatures.</para>

    <para></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>其它Java平台规范</title>

    <para>The following Java API specifications are referenced throughout this
    specification:</para>

    <para>1.Java 2 Platform, Enterprise Edition, v1.4 (J2EE™)</para>

    <para>2.Java Servlet™, v2.4</para>

    <para>3.JavaServer Pages™, v2.0 (JSP™)</para>

    <para>4.The Java™ Architecture for XML Binding (JAXB) 2.0</para>

    <para>These specifications may be found at the Java 2 Platform Enterprise
    Edition website: http://java.sun.com/j2ee/.</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Other Important References</title>

    <para>The following Internet specifications provide information relevant
    to the development and implementation of the Portlet API and standard
    portlet engines:</para>

    <para>1.RFC 1630 Uniform Resource Identifiers (URI)</para>

    <para>2.RFC 1766 Tags for the Identification of Languages</para>

    <para>3.RFC 1738 Uniform Resource Locators (URL)</para>

    <para>4.RFC 2396 Uniform Resource Identifiers (URI): Generic Syntax</para>

    <para>5.RFC 1808 Relative Uniform Resource Locators</para>

    <para>6.RFC 1945 Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP/1.0)</para>

    <para>7.RFC 2045 MIME Part One: Format of Internet Message Bodies</para>

    <para>8.RFC 2046 MIME Part Two: Media Types</para>

    <para>9.RFC 2047 MIME Part Three: Message Header Extensions for non-ASCII
    text</para>

    <para>10.RFC 2048 MIME Part Four: Registration Procedures</para>

    <para>11.RFC 2049 MIME Part Five: Conformance Criteria and Examples</para>

    <para>12.RFC 2109 HTTP State Management Mechanism</para>

    <para>13.RFC 2145 Use and Interpretation of HTTP Version Numbers</para>

    <para>14.RFC 2145 Use and Interpretation of HTTP Version Numbers</para>

    <para>15.RFC 2616 Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP/1.1)</para>

    <para>16.RFC 2617 HTTP Authentication: Basic and Digest
    Authentication</para>

    <para>17.ISO 639 Code for the representation of names of languages</para>

    <para>18.ISO 3166 Code (Country) list</para>

    <para>19.OASIS Web Services for Remote Portlets (WSRP)</para>

    <para>20.CC/PP Processing, JSR 188</para>

    <para>21.W3C: Composite Capability/Preference Profiles (CC/PP): Structure
    and Vocabularies</para>

    <para>Online versions of these RFC and ISO documents are at:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>http://www.rfc-editor.org/</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>http://www.ics.uci.edu/pub/ietf/http/related/iso639.txt</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>http://www.iso.org/iso/en/prods-services/iso3166ma/index.html</para>

    <para></para>

    <para></para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>l</para>

        <para>The World Wide Web Consortium (http://www.w3.org/) is a
        definitive source of HTTP related information affecting this
        specification and its implementations.</para>

        <para>The WSRP Specification can be found in the OASIS web site
        (http://www.oasis-open.org/).</para>

        <para>The Extensible Markup Language (XML) is used for the
        specification of the Deployment Descriptors described in Chapter 13 of
        this specification. More information about XML can be found at the
        following websites:</para>

        <para>http://java.sun.com/xml </para>

        <para>http://www.xml.org/</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>PLT.1.6 Terminology 术语</title>

    <para>The key words MUST, MUST NOT, REQUIRED, SHALL, SHALL NOT, SHOULD,
    SHOULD NOT, RECOMMENDED, MAY, and OPTIONAL in this document are to be
    interpreted as described in [RFC2119].</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>PLT.1.7 Providing Feedback 信息反馈</title>

    <para>We welcome any and all feedback about this specification. Please
    e-mail your comments to jsr-286-comments@jcp.org.</para>

    <para>我们欢迎关于这个规范的任何和所有信息反馈，请发送你的评论到我们的邮件jsr-286-comments@jcp.org.</para>

    <para>Please note that due to the volume of feedback that we receive, you
    will not normally receive a reply from an engineer. However, each and
    every comment is read, evaluated, and archived by the specification
    team.</para>

    <para></para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>PLT.1.8 Acknowledgements V 2.0 鸣谢</title>

    <para>The Portlet Specification V2.0 was the result of the work of JSR286
    Expert Group,</para>

    <para>Subbu Allamaraju, Wesley Budziwojski, Bob Butler, Siddharth
    Chaudhary(Vignette), Padmanabh Dabke,</para>

    <para>David H. DeWolf, Torsten Dettborn, Craig Doremus, Ate Douma, Jorge
    Ferrer (Liferay, 30 LLC), Michael Freedman (Oracle), Kevin Frender (BEA
    Systems), Slava Frid, Deepak</para>

    <para>Gothe(Sun Microsystems, Inc.), Vishal Goenka (SunGard Higher
    Education), Stefan Hepper (IBM Corp.), Martin Holzner (Novell, Inc.),
    Danny Machak (TIBCO Software Inc.), Kito D. Mann, Benjamin Mestrallet (eXo
    Platform SARL), Stephen Millidge, Jason Novotny, Punit Pandey, Ilya Rybak
    (SAP AG), Charles Severance, Hani Suleiman, David Sean Taylor (Apache
    Software Foundation), Julien Viet(JBoss, Inc.), James Ward (Adobe Systems
    Inc.), Carsten Ziegeler (Day).</para>

    <para>We want to give special thanks to (as members of the Expert Group)
    Subbu Allamaraju, Wesley Budziwojski, Craig Doremus, Ate Douma, Michael
    Freedman, Kevin Frender for their major contributions to this
    specification.</para>

    <para>Finally we would like to thank Torsten Dettborn (University of Jena)
    who led the TCK and RI efforts</para>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>PLT.1.9 Acknowledgements V1.0</title>

    <para>The Portlet Specification V1.0 was the result of the work of JSR168
    Expert Group, Subbu Allamaraju (BEA), Chris Braun (Novell), Don Chapman
    (SAS), Michael Freedman (Oracle), Laurent Guiraud (SAP), Randal Hanford
    (Boeing), Andre Kramer (Citrix), Axel Kratel (Borland), Danny Machak
    (TIBCO), Kris Meukens (EDS), Wes Mitchell (Broadvision), Takao Mohri
    (Fujitsu), Dean Moses (Vignette), Andrew Rickard (ATG), William Seiger
    (Sybase), David Sean Taylor (Apache), Stefan Hepper (IBM) and Alejandro
    Abdelnur (Sun).</para>

    <para>We want to give special thanks to (as members of the Expert Group)
    Subbu Allamaraju, Henning Blohm, Chris Braun, Don Chapman, Adrian
    Fletcher, Michael Freedman, Laurent Guiraud, Andre Kramer, Danny Machak,
    Wes Mitchell, Takao Mohri, Dean Moses, Peter Petersen, Andrew Rickard and
    David Sean Taylor for their contributions.</para>

    <para>We would like to thank OASIS WSRP Technical Committee, JSR127 Java
    Server Faces Expert Group and JSR154 Servlet Specification Expert Group
    for their cooperation.</para>

    <para>We would also like to thank all the people who have sent us feedback
    during the Community Review and Public Review stages.</para>

    <para> Finally we would like to thank Maneesha Jain (Sun) and Stephan
    Hesmer (IBM) who led the TCK and RI efforts.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
